Good evening ladies and gentlemen. A
very warm welcome to ICICI Lumbard
General Insurance Company Limited's Q4
FY2024
and FY24 earnings conference call
from the senior management we have with
us today Mr. Sanjie Mantri MD and CEO of
the company Mr. Gopal Balachandran CFO
Mr. Aloc Agarwal executive director
Mr. Girishesh Nayak, Chief Technology
and Health Underwriting and Claims, Mr.
Sep Guradya, Chief Corporate Solutions
Group, and Mr. Anand Singhi, the chief
retail and government business.
Please note that any statements or
comments made in today's call that may
look like forward-looking statements are
based on information presently available
to the management and do not constitute
an indication of any future performance
as the future involves risks and
uncertainties which could cause results
to differ materially from the current
views being expressed.
As a reminder, all participant lines
will be in the listenonly mode. There
will be an opportunity for you to ask
questions after the presentation
concludes.
Should you need assistance during this
conference, please signal an operator by
pressing star and then zero on your
touchstone phone.
I now hand the conference over to Mr.
Sanjie Mantri, MD and CEO, ICICI Lombard
General Insurance Limited. Thank you and
over to you sir. Thank you.
Good evening to each one of you. Thank
you for joining the earning conference
call of ICL Ombar Limited for quarter 4
and financial year 2024.
Let me give you a brief overview of the
industry trends and developments that we
have witnessed in the past few months.
Post this our CFO Mr. Gopal Balatan will
share the financial performance of the
company for the quarter and the year
ended March 31st 2024.
During the quarter, the Indian economy
continued its robust growth trajectory
with key highfrequency indicators
reflecting healthy economic conditions.
For the financial year 2024, India's GDP
growth is expected to be 7.6%.
Looking ahead, a normal southwest
monsoon should support agriculture
activity, boost rural demand, and help
overall sentiments. However, any
worsening of geopolitical tensions or a
global slowdown may have an adverse
impact.
Now, talking about auto industry,
private car sales witnessed robust
growth for the financial year 2024,
aided by improved supplies and sustained
customer demand. As per CM data, over
4.2 million vehicles were sold in the
year. The industry also saw saw a shift
in the customer preference from entry-
levelvel cars to SUV. Thus, contribution
of SUV in private car segment has gone
up from 37% to 49% in last two years.
As mentioned in the ear last earning
calls, uptick in ruler demand saw two
wheeler sales grow by 25%.
In Q4 to touch 4.5 million. The annual
two-wheeler sales also surpassed the
financial year 2020 figure and stood at
18 million vehicles. During the year
around 1.7 million commercial vehicle
were sold which was driven primarily by
good traction in infra and other core
sectors.
Health insurance continued to be the
largest product segment for the industry
as per data published in the ID annual
report for financial year 2023. The
growth in number of lives have been
primary driven by the group health
business and we expect this trend to
continue for financial year 2024 as
well.
The commercial line of business witness
growth supported by strong government
capital expenditure related to
infrastructure development.
Consequently, engineering lines of
business witness a robust growth during
the year.
We remain optimistic that the industry
will continue to grow given the
favorable macros, regulatory changes,
low penetration, and relatively positive
consumer sentiments.
Coming to performance, the general
insurance industry delivered a
year-on-year gross direct premium income
growth of 12.8% for financial year 2024.
Excluding crop and math sales, the
growth stood at 14.8%.
Overall the combined ratio for the
industry was at 112.2% for 9 months
financial year 2024 as against 116.2%
for 9 month financial year 2023. For
motor the combined ratio was at 118.2%
for 9 month financial year 2024 as
against 121.9% for 9 month financial
year 2023.
In our last earning call, we had
mentioned improvement in the industry
combined ratio for motor for H1
financial year 2024 by fin by 400 basis
points to 119.4%
from 123.5% for H1 financial year 2023.
There has been a further improvement of
300 basis points for quarter 3 only in
the combined ratio for motor and 115.9%
as against 118.9% during the same period
last year. The motor combined ratio for
private players in Q3 financial year
2024 was at 110.7%
versus 111.8% for the same period last
year. This improvement indicates a
semblance of discipline coming back to
the market.
As you may be aware, no motor TP hike
has been announced for financial year
2025. As yet, we will be watchful of how
the industry responds to this in coming
days. Now I would like to touch upon
certain regulatory announcements. On
March 28th, 2024, after a comprehensive
review of regulatory framework, the
authority notified a number of principal
based prescriptions. The new regulations
include denotification of all tariffs
notified by the URSW tariff advisory
committee which continued to be inforced
since December 2006.
With the denotification of the existing
tariffs, the company is at the liberty
to design all the general insurance
products in line with its own
underwriting policy. This would
facilitate insurers to respond faster to
the emerging market requirements and to
design innovative products to cater to
customers need. It may be mentioned that
the pricing of motor TP line of business
continues to be under the tariff regime.
Rural, social sector and motor third
party obligation prescribes the minimum
insurance business to be undertaken by
the insurers. The compliance and
measurement of these statutory
obligations has been revised in order to
enhance the insurance penetration.
[Applause]
Sugam insurance electronic marketplace
revolutions allow for establishment of a
digital public infrastructure
insurance electronic marketplace. With
this the authority has set out a vision
of democratizing insurance to achieve
the goal of the insurance for all by
2047.
We believe the regulatory developments
are favorable for the industry. I would
like to further reiterate that as a
company we will as a company we will
continue to leverage the benefits of
being a diversified multi-product and
multi-distribution organization as we
capitalize on the existing and emerging
business opportunities in the sector.
Now I will speak about the business
impact for us in quarter 4 and financial
year 2024.
The company grew by 22% during quarter 4
financial year 2024 excluding a one-off
transaction in the motor segment last
year growth was 15.8% which was higher
than the industry growth of 9.5%
for 9.5%.
For financial year 2024 the company grew
by 17.8% 8% as again the industry growth
of 12.8%.
Excluding the one-off transaction last
year growth for financial year 2024 was
16.4%.
Let me now touch upon our performance in
key business segments during the quarter
and financial year 2024. In the
commercial business segment, we continue
to consolidate our market position by
leveraging our unique distribution
network enhanced by value added
services, prudent risk based
underwriting and highly rated reinsurer
capac capacities.
During quarter 4 2024, we grew at 11.3%
as against an industry growth of 11%.
For financial year 2024, we grew at
14.7% which was higher than the industry
growth of 10%.
Further during the year we acrewed
market shares across segments such as
fire, marine cargo, engineering and
liability.
As we speak we are at an industryleading
position in marine cargo and liability
line of business while being the second
largest in fire and engineering line of
business.
Last year we experienced significant
rate hardening in the reinsurance terms
in line with global trends. However, as
anticipated, the recent April 1st
renewals have largely been benign.
Motor continues to be the largest
contributor to our product mix. Over the
year, we have developed strong
capabilities across distribution,
underwriting, claims, servicing, and
actual practices. Given our presence
across all three subsegments of private
car, two-wheeler, and CV, we would
continue to balance our portfolio mix
depending on the market opportunities.
As we saw some discipline return to the
market, we scaled up our position in a
calibrated manner and consequently
entered the year as an industry leader.
The growth for us during the quarter was
27.3%
excluding the one-off transaction last
year. The growth for quarter 4 2024 was
13.4% as again the industry growth of
9.6%.
For financial year 2024 we grew at 12.3%
excluding the one-off transaction last
year. The annual growth was 8.9% against
the industry growth of 12.9%.
The growth in motor segment was aided by
strong growth in new private car segment
which due at 23% for quarter 4 2024
and 28% for financial year 2024 which
was higher than CM volume growth of 12%
and 8.4% 4% respectively. A new
two-wheer growth was 11% for quarter 4
and 13% for financial year 2024 while
the CM volume growth was 24.9% and 12.3%
respectively.
As real demand picks up, we expect to
see the trend continue for two wheelers.
In the new CB segment, we degrrew by
2.1% in quarter 4 2024 and 1.9% in
financial year 2024. While the slam
volume growth was.1% and 14.4%
respectively.
For financial year 2024, our mix of
private car, two-wheer and commercial
vehicle stands at 51.4%, 26.8%
and 21.9% respectively.
We also continue to build efficiency in
motor claims. In quarter 4 2024, we were
able to service 70% of our agency and
direct claims through preferred partner
network up from 54% in quarter 4 2023.
For the next year, we expect mids
singledigit growth in private car sales
while the two wheeler segment is
expected to deliver 8 to 10% growth. CV
sales are expected to grow in double
digits in line with the previous year on
account of demand from infrastructure.
The health the health segment continued
to be the fastest growing segment for
the industry. We grew faster than the
industry both in quarter 4 and financial
year 2024 registering a growth of 29%
for the quarter and full year.
The group health employer employee
segment we grew at 31.7% in quarter 4
2024 and 30.3% in financial year 2024.
The change in the underlying industry
pricing sentiments resulted in customer
moving towards insurers with superior
servicing capabilities.
Our retail health business grew by 21.8%
in quarter 4 2024 against the industry
growth of 19.9%.
For financial year 2024 our retail
growth view retail business view at 20%
as against and the industry growth at
19.1%.
We would continue to invest in this
segment in terms of human technology,
human uh human capital, technology and
knowledge capital to further improve our
market share. Our current retail
agency manager count stands at 1600. We
will continue to strengthen our growth
rework as we expect to achieve far more
than far more in this segment. Our bank
insurance and key relationship grew at
16.7% for the quarter and 20.2% 2% for
the financial year 2024.
Within this ICICA group distribution
grew by 39.4%
for quarter 4 financial year 2024 and
22.5% for financial year 2024. We will
continue to deepine our existing
relationships by creating new value
streams and at the same time focus on
acquiring new relationship. During the
year we added over 80 banker
partnerships.
In our last call we spoke about our
vision of one is one team. Under this
one of our initiative that we had
outlined in our one eye is our one is
one digital strategy. Through this we
aim to consolidate our customerf facing
digital assets of take care website and
alliances along with our distribution
facing front ends. This will allow us to
exploit the synergies across all our
platforms which will result in benefits
to the company.
Our one-stop solution for all insurance
and wellness needs, the I take care app
has surpassed 9.3 million user downloads
till date. We continue our growth
momentum with8 million user downloads
for the quarter. In the same period, we
source premium over 1.13 billion and a
premium of 3.68 billion for financial
year 2024, registering a 3x increase on
a Y basis.
Our overall customerf facing digital
business grew at 29.5% in quarter 4 and
39% in financial year 2024 and
constitutes 6.8% and 6% respectively of
our overall business. Last week we
announced a strategic tie up with policy
bazar. Our tie-up is aimed at leveraging
the strength of the two institutions to
create a superior customer value
proposition.
After transitioning into cloud, we have
continued to make significant
investments on modernization of our
technology platform.
Along with this, our core business and
technology transformation project Orion
is also underway. Project Toan would
entail three pivotal pillars of
reimagining processes with a digital
first approach, modernizing technology
by shifting away from legacy systems and
enhancing stakeholders experience to
superior enhance engagement models. We
are excited to share that we have
kickstarted the transformation journey
with some of our preferred line of
businesses and are witnessing the
initiatives shaping up nicely. We firmly
believe project will be a key enabler on
our vision of one I one team. As we
empire on the new financial year, we
will focus on leveraging our
multi-product multi-distribution
strategy through effective use of data
digital advancements and launching new
products. We'll maintain focus on
scaling up our profit pool while
continuing to grow as one, one team. Now
I would request Gup could take you
through the financial numbers for the
year for the recently concluded quarter
and the year. Thanks Ajivie and uh good
evening to each one of you. I will now
give you a brief overview of the
financial performance of the recently
concluded quarter and financial year. We
have uploaded the results presentation
on our website. You can access it as we
walk you through the performance
numbers. During the quarter IC bank
acquired additional equity shares of the
company. Consequently, the shareholding
of the bank in the company has increased
to more than 50% and the company has
become a subsidiary of the bank. Gross
direct premium income of the company was
at rupes 247.76 billion in FI24 as
against rupees 210.25 billion in FI23, a
growth of 17.8%
which was higher than the industry
growth of 12.8%. Excluding crop and mass
health, the GDP growth of the company
was at 17.1%
which was higher than the industry
growth of 14.8% 8% in FI24.
GDP of the company was at rupees 60.73
billion in quarter 4 FI24 as against
rupes 49.77 billion in quarter 4 FI23 a
growth of 22%. This growth was higher
than the industry growth of 9.5%.
Excluding crop and mass sales GDPI
growth was at 22% which was again higher
than the industry growth of 13.8% in
quarter 4 FI24. Our GDP growth during
FI24 was primarily driven by growth in
the preferred segments. The overall GDP
growth of our property and casualty
segment grew by 14.7% at rupees 68.51
billion in FI24 as against rupes 59.73
billion in FI23. On the retail side of
the business, GDP of the motor segment
was at rupes 96.34 billion in FI24 as
against rupees 85.82 billion in FI23
registering a growth of 12.3%.
The advanced premium was at rupees 33.3
billion at March 31, 2024 as against
rupes 33.04 billion as at December 31,
2023. GDP of the health segment was at
rupees 61.71 billion in FI24 as against
rupees 47.82 billion in FI23 registering
a growth of 29.1%. Our agents which
included the point of sale distribution
count was at 128411
as on March 31, 2024 up from 125088 as
on December 31, 2023. During the year we
witnessed catastrophic events namely
cyclone vipperjoy, north Indian floods
and cyclone machong. Resultedly combined
ratio was 103.3% for the full year FI24
as against 104.5% for FI23.
Excluding the impact of these CAT losses
of rupees 1.37 billion for the full year
the combined ratio would have been at 1
102.5%.
For the quarter combined ratio was
102.2% in quarter 4 FI24 as against
104.2% in quarter 4 of FI23.
Our investment assets rose to rupes
489.07 billion as at March 31 2024 up
from rupes 468.67 billion as at December
31 2023. Our investment leverage net of
borrowings was 4.09 times as at March
31, 2024 as against 4.11 times as at
December 31, 2023. Investment income was
at rupes 35.26 billion in FI24 as
against rupees 29.77 billion in FI23. On
a quarterly basis, investment income was
at rupees 9.3 billion in Q4 this year as
against rupees 8.17 billion in Q4 of
last year. Our capital gains net of
impairment investment assets stood at
rupees 5.51 billion in FI24 as compared
to rupees 4.53 billion in FI23. Capital
gains net of impairment investment
assets stood at rupees 1.56 billion in
quarter 4 FI24 as compared to rupees
1.59 billion in quarter 4 FI23. Our
profit before tax grew by 21% at rupes
25.55 billion in FI24 as against rupes
21.13 billion in FI23 whereas profit
before tax grew by 21.9% at rupees 6.98
billion in Q4 FI24 as against 5.73
billion in Q4 FI23.
Consequently profit after tax grew by
11% at rupes 19.19 billion in FI24 as
against rupes 17.29 29 billion in FI23.
Excluding the impact of reversal of tax
provision in Q2 FI23, profit after tax
grew by 19.8% in FI24. Profit after tax
grew by 18.9% at rupees 5.2 billion in
Q4 FI24 from rupees 4.37 billion in Q4
FI23. The board of directors has
proposed a final dividend of rupees 6
per share for FI24. This payment is
however subject to approval of
shareholders in the ensuing annual
general meeting of the company. The
overall dividend for FI24 including the
proposed final dividend is rupes 11 per
share. Last year the overall dividend
was rupes 10 per share. Return on
average equity was 17.2% in FI24 as
again 17.7% in FI23. Return on average
equity for the quarter 4 FI24 was 17.8%
as again 17.2% in quarter 4 FI23.
Solveny ratio was at 2.62 times at March
31, 2024 as against 2.57 times as at
December 31, 2023 continued to be higher
than the minimum regulatory requirement
of 1.5 times. As I conclude, I would
like to reiterate that we continue to
stay focused on driving profitable
growth, sustainable value creation, and
safeguarding interest of policy holders
at all times. We would uh we would like
to thank you all for attending this
earnings call and we'll be happy to take
any questions uh at this point.
Thank you.
Thank you very much. We will now begin
the question and answer session. Anyone
who wishes to ask a question may press
star and one on their touchstone
telephone.
If you wish to withdraw yourself from
the question queue, you may press star
and two. Participants are requested to
please use handsets while asking a
question. Ladies and gentlemen, we will
now wait for a moment while the question
queue assembles.
The first question comes from the line
of Shrea Shivani from CLSA. Please go
ahead.
Thank you and um congratulations on a
good set of numbers. I have three
questions. Uh so first is on the overall
growth outlook. So a health book for us
has done quite well since past two
years. Since FI22 the growth has been
north of 25 30 40% right uh so so
um expecting some moderation in growth
going ahead what will be the key drivers
for growth in FI 2526 uh which segments
would be driving majority of the growth
and how much higher than industry growth
can we deliver in the years to come
given that motor segment is still the
the combined ratio is still though there
has been an improvement and discipline
has come in but it's still quite a high
combined ratio for us to for one to
expect us to grow very fast in the motor
segment. So that's my first question on
key growth drivers and how much faster
than industry can we grow in FI2526.
Uh second is on the motor TP segment. Uh
looking at the reserve triangles
reserving triangle for the motor segment
TP segment specifically. So there has
been a much higher reserve release in
accident year 18 1920. I mean the trend
looks much better than the previous
prior year trend. So how should we read
this data? Does this also significantly
add to your FI24 loss ratio improvement
on YI basis? Uh apart from more new card
being sold. Um so that's that's my
second question. And sir on the third
question is on the combined ratio we've
done quite well on the combined ratio
side. Um already atund for the fourth
quarter that has gone gone by much
better uh numbers over there. So um
going ahead what is our guidance on
combined ratio and one question that I
also asked at the analyst meet about uh
considering uh natural calamities as
business as usual going ahead does that
change our combined ratio guidance in
any these are my three questions thank
you
uh so so I just let go take the other
one and I'll tell you what what is our
view yeah so I think uh if you look at
uh on the first one sh I think uh if you
look at it from an overall market
perspective If uh I think as we have
always been saying we have been we have
always been looking at this business in
the context of being a multi-product
multi-distribution setup and therefore
to that extent uh different segment of
businesses uh presents opportunities for
growth maybe at different points of time
and hence to that extent is where I
think we have been able to kind of put
in place a model in place by which we
are able to leverage the growth
potential u so and it is in that context
when you look at the overall year gone
by I think we have been able to have an
outperformance relative to the market
growth and if you look at in terms of
how we are heading into the next year I
think there's a lot of positive momentum
that we see from from an overall market
perspective as well one of course the
slew of uh regulatory reforms that we
spoke as a part of the introductory uh
remarks I think that augers well both
from a market standpoint and even from
the opportunity that it gives for ISIS I
think it's very very positive
Second, I think if you look at the
thrust that the government is putting on
in terms of in general looking at
significant thrust of infrastructure
development that obviously presents a
lot more opportunities on multiple
segments of businesses whether you look
at it in the commercial line space uh
maybe for example uh thrust on
engineering projects to begin with.
Obviously to that extent it kind of aids
in logistics uh transportation to again
look at uh growth profitably and more
importantly it is also expected to lead
to let's say higher number of uh uh jobs
and therefore to that extent it as I
said kind of augers very well uh in
terms of the opportunity that one sees
specific to your point on health I think
as we have always said even in the past
I think uh the kind of opportunity that
one sees in the market if you look
Few years back the market was
significantly stressed in terms of the
loss experience or and more importantly
whether you look at it from a combined
issue standpoint given that some of the
players are already kind of looking at
uh reversing some element of pricing
within group health and particularly on
the employer employee side it obviously
kind of augers well and that's reason
why you see us uh continuing to grow
disproportionately relative to the
market and even as we head into FI 25 we
believe health for for the industry as
well will continue to be by far the one
of the fastest growing segments and
within that even for ISIS Lombard we see
an opportunity on health both in the
group's health as well as from the
retail health uh segments uh so that's
whe whether the growth will be
continuing to be at 25 will it slightly
get moderated I think we will obviously
wait for things to evolve but honestly
as we have said even in the past I don't
think uh from a market perspective we
continue to see prolonged periods of 25
to 30% growth from an industry
standpoint. So I think that's something
that we will obviously watch for. The
second question on yours in terms of the
motor third party reserving triangle, I
think uh it's good that the market is
starting to look at the triangle
disclosures uh from an overall market
perspective. I think that again augers
well because then every company is being
kind of pro to appropriate uh level of
scrutiny from a market perspective and
else to that extent it again uh augers
well from an overall market discipline.
uh in terms of uh uh the some of the
let's say the releases that you spoke
about I think if you ask us the way I
would kind of respond to it is whether
have we is there any change in the
approach of our reserving philosophy the
approach is not changed and in line with
what we have been speaking even in the
earlier quarters I think the way to look
at on the third party book as you
rightly mentioned is more more on an
annual basis and in fact if you recolct
uh even last time in the quarter
earnings call we did speak about a range
within in which we see the loss
experience play out for motor as a
category and just to kind of refresh
that we had said motor own damage loss
experience is something that we see in
the range of 60 to 65%. And motor third
party as a segment we had said we would
be kind of operating at a range between
65 to 70%. And both of that blended is
where we had said motor as a category
would run in that range of 64 65%. And
if you look at the full year numbers
both on motor own damage as well as on
motor third party I think broadly the
outcome of the book that we have been
able to underwrite has been within that
range that I just kind of uh refreshed.
Having said that one of the key
deliverables that we would obviously
watch for which also put which we put as
a part of the uh introductory remarks is
on motor third party pricing. Now as we
speak statement of fact is we have not
seen a price change. uh so we will watch
for development in that space and
therefore to that extent the risk
selection will continue to be driven by
some of the factors that we see at peak
in terms of no price increase thus far
so we'll be guided more by that in terms
of how we see the opportunity the range
of loss experiences is a function of
what I kind of mentioned your last point
on combined ratio
I think uh shares clearly I mean the
quarter four numbers on the combined
ratio which reached that 102.2 two and
there about where does it place his
overall commentary in terms of what we
have spoken tail events available
sectoral reforms which are being
initiated by the regulator uh we see a
play and we do see that we can have a
you know overall 50 basis improvements
further to what we had said we will
achieve as a team by quarter four of
next year
but uh again we will keep revisiting and
absolutely we'll keep communicating but
we do see green shoots and we that kind
of an improvement can come in overall
for us as an entity.
So, so what you're saying basically by
FI25 we were targeting 102 that can be
uh 50 books u lower at 101.5 unless
there is some other and what about the
catastrophe events are we are we still
watching it or have we come to a
conclusion on how we should be dealing
with yes uh so clearly I think Gopar
also in the past has been mentioning
that the frequency of catastrophic event
on an annual basis uh has uh got
increased And do we factor that when we
speak about it? Yes, there is a level of
factoring. But like last year was an
exceptional one which was more than the
factoring. That's why we keep stitching
in terms of what would have happened if
those cat events would not have been in
terms of quantum to that extent. Uh
we are in the business of writing risk
at a fundamental level. Do we watch? Do
we factor? All of that is part of the
process but the extent the extent of the
event is something which we all await.
uh we will keep you updated on that
part. But there's some element which
obviously is big deal when we see that
uh we are overall expecting an
improvement of 50 basis points.
Okay. Sure. So thank thank you. This is
useful. Thank you. Thank you.
Ladies and gentlemen, we request you to
please restrict your questions to two
questions per participant.
We have the next question from the line
of Sankit Goda from Aventus Park. Please
go ahead. Uh yeah uh thank you thank you
for the opportunity. I have two key
question. Uh one one question is with
the with respect to the regulation. Um
just just my my understanding of that
new obligation norms on motor TP seems
to be more stringent than it was in the
previous regime. So so just wanted to
understand whether whether we would be
confident to fulfill the obligation of
motor PP in the new norms. uh is is the
point we wanted to I mean just wanted to
understand and and how you will achieve
it that's that's one question and and
second strategic question which I want
to understand is that you you have
highlighted about 1L um uh but but if
you want to quantify the number uh due
to 1L what are the synergies you are
expecting to see either in the form of
GWP growth because because you're now
aligning agents across the business
segment or distribution across the
segments so so so you expect the
synergies and and if I mean quantify the
number in terms terms of GWP, additional
GWP or or maybe an additional
improvement in the expense ratio because
of these synergies and and lastly on
data keeping uh uh if you can share
retail and group health loss ratio and
and Gopal to last point sorry uh that
that if if the no PP price hike doesn't
come are you still confident that 65 to
70 motor TP loss ratio is achievable or
not
okay so I'll take the first two and then
the other one uh other that the the data
that you're seeking in the last question
Gopal will come in and give it to you.
Uh in terms of the new TP regulations
that have come in see I mean the
insurance the authority has clearly said
that they're looking for insurance for
all by 2047 and for that some initiation
has to be done. Uh the contours of how
this will uh emerge for all of us has
still to emerge. uh it's kind of work in
progress but that being said we are
multi-line multi-product well
distributed franchise is so much of
retail I mean the amount of people we do
uh as an entity is humongous so we are
present we would definitely back
ourselves to achieve uh uh the
objectives that are set by the regulator
but we would be speculating beyond the
point as to where we where we will be
placed till we have complete clarity in
terms of what's expected from us so
that's point number on under one uh one
team that we have been talking about and
really emphasizing uh quantification
fundamentally comes with the quarter
results that you will see us announcing
and we would uh refrain from attaching
uh you know finite value because the
overall performance is subject to
scrutiny which we keep announcing to all
of you and uh uh are we excited in terms
of uh seeing both topline and cost uh
for getting you know controlled in a
relatively better manner. So the answer
is yes definitely and we do believe
coming quarters will acrue but we will
not be you know culling it out and
calling that this has happened because
of this overall the efficiency of the
company will be you know will be
reflected in how we perform as an entity
and there are multiple other aspects
that come you know we may have some
genuine savings we may choose to
reinvest also that so we would not like
to uh you know dwell on this on those
aspects uh SI
but you give away 50 basis points better
guidance than than what it was last
year. So, so is it because of this 1L
what you are trying to uh
again seek I what I what I would again
you know you know rush into I get from
where your uh excitement is coming from
this would be one of the countries we
have always maintained that the industry
sentiments also has to move in the
positive direction and we have always
maintained the fact that we would be an
output of where the overall industry
growth is and how our own placement is.
So uh is this an element that comes in
and binds us together as an
organization? 110% answer is yes. Uh but
to quantify this from this output this
much has come because of one team will
not be uh will not be fair is all I'm
saying. So there are multiple things
that go in that. Uh for the other two
questions that you had I'll ask Gopal to
revert to you. Yeah. So, so on the
health loss numbers, uh again I'll give
you Q4 numbers first and then I will
give you the full year numbers. Q4 on
the uh GHI which is employer employee
segment this is for quarter 4 of last
year which is FI23 that number is at
93.2%.
That number for quarter 4 of this year
is at 88.1%.
uh and on a fullear basis for the same
segment I think the range that we have
spoken about is to operate in the range
of 94 95%. If you look at FI23 the
overall loss ratio on the GHI site was
95.2%.
And this year we are at about 937%.
On retail health again just to kind of
refresh uh what we have talked about
even in the past several quarters is
we're comfortable operating in the loss
ratio range which is between 65 to 70%.
In that context when you look at the
quarter 4 FI23 numbers retail which is
on the uh indemnity side that loss ratio
was about 61%.
That number for quarter 4 of this year
is at 64.6%.
And on a full year basis last year
number was 64.1
and the current year number is at about
65.4. Uh so that's in in response to
your second point on the health loss
numbers. the last question of yours in
in terms of uh whether the range that I
spoke about of 65 to 70% in the context
of motor third party uh so again I think
that's the range that we have kind of
largely operated at I think the only
factor that I would say is uh in line
with again what we've been speaking even
in the past few quarters as in to say
that what we are seeing on ground is
also maybe an increased preference of
the courts to start giving compensation
in favor of uh the victim victims of the
insured and therefore so that's a trend
that we will obviously observe. Uh the
other factor which would again uh which
we have which we have again spoken of
which should be directionally positive
is also this whole 6 months law
limitation in terms of how that gets
played out. Uh last year of course we
did see some developments and finally as
we have been saying the matter is
presently at the Supreme Court. Once the
verdict comes out I think we will again
have to see in terms of how that plays
gets played out on ground. So hence
there are again balancing forces in
terms of ones that could possibly see or
reflect an increase in the loss
experience that's purely then it's up to
us in terms of what kind of risk
selection do we do and the second is
more a positive benefit at least for IC
lumbar from an overall RU accretion
standpoint and hence to that extent that
that should kind of aid us in terms of
maintaining the loss ratio range of 65
to 70%. So there are a lot of moving
parts. Now at this point of time I think
we would want to kind of stick with uh
the 65 to 70% range and of course we
will see some of these factors in terms
of how that gets paid out through the
years.
Uh perfect. Thanks. Thanks for your
responses. Thank you. Thanks. Okay.
Thank you.
The next question is from the line of
Nidesh from Invest. Please go ahead. Uh
thanks for the opportunity. Uh first
question is on FRS. So any uh any update
what are the timelines for expected
implementation of IFRS and what impact
on our our balance sheet of
so Nesh I think again in line with what
I had mentioned even in the last
earnings call. I think we had said that
uh we are pretty much progressing well
in terms of doing the impact assessment
making sure that we get ourselves uh
ready for the implementation which is
effective from FI 256 financial year. Uh
and even last quarter we did say that we
will come back in maybe couple of
quarters time frame. So honestly
internally while we are doing all of
those and also watching for uh the
developments in terms of all the
necessary guidelines and standards
getting issued in the context of the
IFRS transition. So therefore at this
point of time too early to call out but
as I always maintained I think we have
clearly spoken about three or four key
uh areas or aspects which is where we
would likely to see the impact of
transition play out in the context of so
that doesn't change um whether it is in
terms of acquisition cost whether it is
in terms of discounting of reserves
whether it is in terms of marktomarket
on the investment book and maybe for few
set of companies which have kind of
issued uh let's say stock units or stock
options So there will be an element of
uh cost through the earnings. So those
are three or four key areas where one
would see an impact of the transition
play out. Specifically to call out, I
think we will come back and obviously
keep all of you updated in terms of uh
where we are on the IFRS transition.
Sure. Sure. And uh secondly uh in terms
of solveny ratio, we are operating at
significantly higher number versus the
region threshold. Uh and our roe have
also now improved to 17 to 18%. Uh so uh
do you think of better utilization of
capital going forward?
No, of course that's obviously something
that we kind of uh uh is something that
we always look for. uh I think one of
the factors that you see which also led
to let's say improvement in solveny and
of course improvement in earnings over
the last few years has been our approach
to as what Sanjiv has also been talking
about is to sustain profitable growth as
a theme and hence in let's say relative
to the market I think we have been
slightly slowing going slow on some of
the segments and therefore to that
extent we have not been able to
completely utilize the solveny capital
what we are seeing is what we kind of
put out as a part of the introductory
remark which is to say that on ground we
are seeing semblance coming back in uh
some of the segments where we have we
have been a bit cautious and therefore
to that extent as we see let's say
incremental growth play out in line in
line with our approach to continue to
grow as well as kind of remain
profitable obviously there will be
consumption of capital that one would
see uh in terms of uh the way forward uh
and secondly I think the approach or the
philosophy that is always worked with is
to
slightly more prudent in terms of the
level of solveny that we want to
maintain given the fact that Indian
market still continues to operate on a a
solveny one regime while again uh thanks
to the regulator they have been
significantly working on getting the
market again transition to a risk based
capital regime obviously we will get to
know more in terms of the firm date of
uh implementation uh in terms of the
transition uh so hence that that that's
something again that we will see in
terms of How does that result into in so
far as the consumption of capital is
concerned? So while we do see growth
opportunities and hence to that extent
we believe we will continue to use the
capital uh judiciously.
So and just lastly on the provision for
diminish in value of investment of
around 68 crores. Uh what is the reason
for that and uh when we disclose the
gain number what is excluding this?
Please rejoin the queue for follow-up
questions.
Okay sir. All right. Thank you.
The next question is from the line of PR
Jen from Motila Los. Please go ahead. Uh
yeah hi good evening. Uh so firstly just
a clarification when you say 101.5 as a
guidance that is for the exit rate of Q4
of next year or it's for the uh full
year. Uh secondly, if I you know like
just uh just going back to one of the uh
previous questions on the uh motor TP
business on your uh you know the
obligation if the share of CV goes up do
you still uh believe that that's you
know 65 to 70% guidance can be
maintained um and within that you know
Gopal time and again you know we've seen
Q4 loss ratios improve sequentially
increase sequentially for motor TP. Uh
is it just because of the adverse
judgments that come in Q4 or what is it
that really gives that kind of a loss
ratio uptrend in every fourth quarter?
Uh yeah, I think those would be my two
questions. Yeah. Yeah, maybe I'll take
the the uh uh TP loss ratio part first.
uh I think whenever there is let's say
possible uh reduction in the TP loss
ratios the questions gets asked the
other way around so and therefore to
that extent uh I think as I think I have
always kind of maintained that this is a
book which is much more longtail in
terms of loss development and therefore
to that extent given the nature of the
business you will always see
cyclicality/ fluctuations in the loss
experience of the book in terms of its
outcome so therefore which is why I keep
harping on looking at the numbers
ideally over longer term but definitely
not between quarters look at it more on
an annual basis um and as I keep saying
again there are various factors that
influences uh let's say the loss
experience of the book I think uh so
hence to that extent you will get to see
fluctuations in the TP loss ratios
across quarters on a full year basis is
what I spoke about in terms of trying to
maintain us operating at a segment uh I
mean segment loss ratio in that range of
65 to 70%
Uh now coming back to your first second
part of the question in terms of link to
motor third party is the obligation. Now
obviously the the obligation is
something that is applicable to industry
at large and therefore as an as a
company I mean uh we have to make sure
that we kind of meet those uh
obligations and I'm sure we will have in
place a plan by virtue of which we are
able to meet uh the regulatory
expectations. I think the the thought
process in terms of where the regulator
is coming out with the need to bring
about this change is again very very
positive because the whole thought
process is to try and make sure that the
industry kind of comes under the ambit
of insurance and to that extent that's
very very positive and if you're able to
do as a as an industry if you're able to
work collectively and maybe bring the
larger set of let's say uninsured
vehicles within the ambit of insurance
that to my mind is a great positive and
hence to that extent I think we would
obviously work and make sure that we
able to meet those uh obligations on the
third party side. uh is the first part
on the combined ratio uh uh part I think
obviously yes I think directionally the
lens that we have talked about Miz is
pre is uh that we have we have been
saying that directionally the uh
trajectory for us is to bring down the
combined over a period of time and
obviously this has to be looked at in
the context of how we see the market
environment operate at uh which is why I
think even as a part of the introductory
remark we did point out to say that the
market is clearly showing signs of at
least from the reported numbers on a
9-month basis there is almost a 400
basis point improvement in combined uh
from an overall market perspective and
within that one of the key segment which
has been a larger contributor of
significant competitive intensity has
been motor now that's again a segment
which has again not just on a half
yearly basis even if you look at the
quarterly quarter three numbers for the
market that's again shown an improvement
of almost about 300 basis point so which
is why I think we kind of put out to say
that there seems to be some kind of a
semblance coming back and That's also
getting reflected in terms of the growth
numbers that many of these players were
exhibiting in terms of competitive
aggression. Clearly you can see a lot
many players are starting to kind of
pull back. So that gives us possibly
some kind of a confidence uh in terms of
how do we look at achieving that uh
combined objective that we laid out and
hence to that extent even in the past I
think what we have maintained is what I
mean if the market environment is
favorable there is no reason why we
would not be able to accelerate the
expectations of combined and that is
where we are that is why we stand and uh
and and in all finance we hope to kind
of achieve uh the thought process that
we laid out from a combined perspective
it's full it's for the full here right
that's the clarification I was so uh as
things stand and probably we'll be in
touch on this uh pre we believe the
exact will be uh overall with the 50
basis less uh there are serious plans of
investments also we would uh continue to
update as the quarters unfold because as
Gopal said these are early signs that
makes us optimistic and sees the
visibility of this uh but uh there are
multiple things that will unfold as of
now in our mind it would be probably
exit by quarter four is where we would
see this and if it gets further
accelerated we'll come back and uh
connect with you all by end of quarter
one of this year. Great. Thank and all
the best.
Thank you.
We have the next question from the line
of Madukar Lada from Noama Wealth.
Please go ahead.
Uh hi uh congratulations on a good set
of numbers. So most of my questions have
been answered. I wanted to understand uh
investment yields have improved uh again
uh this quarter and even if we exclude
um even if we exclude the capital gains
uh we're doing quite well. So uh what is
the number that we should be sort of
looking at in this and uh what is the
duration how are we driving this
actually that's that is one question on
my end thank you yeah sure will yeah so
again madukar I think uh again I would
kind of respond this in the context of
I'm sure you guys know is it far better
I think obviously investments have to be
looked at in terms of it return profile
over a period of time uh and hence to
that extent is how what we keep saying
is to look at market opportunities in
terms of uh having a blended mix of the
right asset classes between both fixed
income and equity and that's what we
have been kind of looking at over the
period of time in terms of realizing the
opportunities. Now specifically to
answer an point on what led to let's say
the increase in the uh interest yield or
let's say the overall return on the
portfolio is it is in line with the high
higher interest rate regime that we have
seen and obviously one leverages the
opportunity and even if you look at
historical past in terms of what kind of
a mix of our overall returns have been
in terms of interest across to let's say
capital gains that mix has broadly been
on the interest acral side in the range
of 75 to 80%. and on the capital gain
side a number that could range between
15 to 20 20 25% around that kind of a
threshold. So hence to that extent is
how we see the opportunity play out and
specifically if you look at our yield to
maturity uh on the fixed income side the
yield to maturity currently stands at
about 7.4%. Uh so hence and that's the
that's the opportunity that one was able
to seize in the market and uh now can we
sustain this? Obviously, we will have to
wait and see how the interest rate cycle
play out. Uh there are clear
expectations that you will start seeing
some kind of a rate reduction cycle play
through at some point of time. Again,
we're positioned well even to capitalize
that opportunity. But what could happen
at those points is our ability to
reinvest those uh realized flows will
obviously get invested at a lower return
on the uh approval side. But obviously
we are well positioned to capitalize the
opportunity from a capital gains
standpoint. And therefore now to answer
your point on the overall range of
returns that we can operate with again
if you look at FI23 I think the overall
return on the realized book was roughly
at about 7.5%. This number if you look
at for FI24 was roughly at about 7.98
closer to 8%. Um and the range I mean
internally the range that we kind of run
with is to kind of give a return profile
between 7 to 7 and a half%. And but over
our last now that we are almost into
23rd 24th year of operations I think the
return profile has been definitely
better than that particular range. So
that's the range that we would be
comfortable with and hence that extent
uh is where we would like to operate at
thanks thanks very helpful. Thank you.
Thanks for the cut.
Thank you.
Ladies and gentlemen, we will now take
the last question for today from the
line of Aditi Jooshi from JP Morgan.
Please go ahead.
Uh yes sir. Uh thank you for my question
taking my question. Uh just one uh
followup question um which I wanted to
uh understand from you on the compet uh
the investment intensity in the channel.
Uh so for the uh full year 2025 what is
the outlook as been of the investments
uh in the channel uh in terms of the
intensity are you going to increase uh
further or just wait for the investments
the last in the last couple of years to
cryptify and then uh just some guidance
on that will be helpful. So uh so again
if you look at I think what we put out
even as a part of the introductory
comment is I think just to kind of
refresh again I think we always looked
ourselves as a multi-distribution uh
company and therefore to that extent is
how we see opportunity play out across
different channels if you ask us would
we stay entranced with each of these
channels the answer is a clear yes I
think in so far as let's say as we see
new motor vehicle sales gaining momentum
and therefore to that extent obviously
we will kind of leverage on the access/
partnerships that we have been able to
create historically of working with
OEMs/ more importantly the dealership
touch points and that's the reason if
you look at across years the proportion
of dealership access that we have had
out of the total number of dealerships
as a country again just to kind of
refresh that number used to be between
50 to 55% at the time when we did our
listing currently we have been able to
reach that number closer to in slightly
upward course of 65% uh in terms of the
total number of dealership. So that will
continue to be an important channel of
distribution agency which kind of
encompasses between motor health has
always been an area of opportunity and
that's a segment which obviously we have
been kind of expanding a lot more and
clearly we have seen benefits of the
investments play out whether you look at
on theme I think the growth rates over
the last several years have been very
positive even on let's say I would say
uh agency motor I think that's a segment
where we have talked about trying to
create a balanced mix between
dealership, agency and let's say our
direct distribution. So hence to that
extent obviously we will continue to
leverage on uh motor agency specifically
and in specific since we're talking in
the context of agency retail health is
always a positive opportunity that one
sees uh and that's the reason why we put
out that number of the headcount that we
have on our own health agency managers
which is currently at about 1,600 and we
would want to continue to see expansion
in that particular space. So you will
obviously see a lot more expansion
initiatives being undertaken in the
context of retail health and therefore
to that extent that should logically
translate into an improved market share
uh in that particular segment. While
even this year we would have loved to
have done better but honestly we have
not been able to completely leverage the
uh opportunity that one sees but given
the fact that we have been able to uh
strengthen our leadership team as well I
think one would expect a lot more to
happen in terms of expanding
distribution launching new products and
obviously strengthening the technology
deliverables uh so that's agency will
continue to be a very very important
channel of sourcing and Sanjiv in the
last earning calls did speak about one
digital
uh channel and therefore that will again
continue to be a very very important
channel of sourcing and if you look at
just from the current year standpoint
the overall contribution of the digital
opportunity that spans across take care
website alliance partners etc etc that
contribution has been almost in the
range of about 6 to 7% of the overall
revenues and that's again kind of
compounding well in in excess of almost
about 20% yearonear so all in all I
think uh it is going to be a combination
of all channels I there is going to be
thrust of investments in each of them.
If you ask me which channel will by far
gain the maximum traction, obviously
retail health is an area where we would
want to kind of significantly leverage
faster and then of course we have the
digital opportunity that one sees and
then we will continue to leverage on the
other channels of and more importantly I
just I did miss one of them which is the
bank partnerships. I think again that
will be a very very important area of
sourcing and within that ICI group will
be a very very important contribution
for us and hence we would obviously want
to leverage on each of these channels of
distribution.
Sure. Thank you very much. Can I can I
just squeeze in one more? Can you please
uh share your outlook of the health
pricing both in the retail and the
group? Uh that would be helpful. Thank
you. outlook on health insurance
uh pricing pricing the the health
insurance pricing yeah in both the
retail segment as well as in the group I
think uh it's it's it's a function of
loss issue and as you said we will
continue to be a prudent uh underwriter
uh in both the segments uh most of the
industry including us have taken a hike
on the retail health side uh last year
so uh we would believe as things stand
we would like to operate in this range.
Uh and while we will obviously keep
revisiting in terms of frequency as well
as the loss ratio that comes along with
it but uh that's what our view on retail
health is. The group health is far more
dynamic and uh driven by multiple you
know factors uh in the market. Uh is it
holding up overall? Yes. There has been
some bit of a discipline that continues
to exist and is that's what it stays
then we would obviously stay relevant.
If it does not work out for us, we would
not hesitate to move away and let go
that business if it's not making sense.
That guarantee we have and we always
maintain I again reiterate that uh
profit pools keep moving uh and
accordingly we have to be agile as an
organization. We will take those calls
uh uh because we want to to the best of
our effort want to ensure that we
deliver what the market is expecting
with us uh with a multi-line multi
product company like us.
Thank you very much. Thanks. Thank you.
Thank you. I would now like to hand the
conference over to Mr. Sanjie Mantri for
closing comments. Over to you sir. Now
thank you so much for joining then. Uh
it's an auspicious day of Ram Navari and
probably some of you at holiday. Uh it's
always a pleasure uh interacting with
all of you. the opportunity as it stays
the momentum that we have developed. Uh
we are excited about the opportunity
ahead. Uh look forward to interacting
with you in time to come and all the
best. Take care. Thank you so much.
Thank you. On behalf of ICICI Lombard
General Insurance Company Limited, that
concludes this conference. Thank you all
for joining us. You may now disconnect
your lines.